Episode 16
Project coordinator and song translator: Nemie
Translators: Nemie, Kaia
You should leave quickly
Shut up
I will protect you
Beta Editor: Sana
Brother! Let us go!
Please!
If you let us go, I will never return to Goryeo!
Think about how we grew up together
Brother!
Darling
Doc...
It's okay, Doc, it's okay.
Doc, everything's fine. We'll live together, right?
Doc?
Doc!
Doc! No...
Doc, don't
Soon Deok
Soon Duk...
Out of the way
Is it necessary to go that far?
The roots of treason must be destroyed so that the people can live in peace.
Go away
Enough!
Eun!
Remember my birthday?
You said you would give me any gift
Remember this?
I said there was only one thing you could give me
He made me say it
This girl...
I won't let her go alone
Brother,
I would like such a gift
Only you can give it
No...
The flower will fall to the ground, it withered
He will be all alone, so sad
Eun!
The sky will lose its stars, it will instantly become sad
No! Brother! Brother!
Brother? Brother?
Brother?
B-brother...wake up, huh?
Brother! Open your eyes!
And suddenly it starts crying like a little rain
Brother...
It feels like a flower blooms and then withers
Tell me with the wind, please
With the appearance of snow, all dreams will come true
Oh, darling, aren't you waiting for me?
With all my heart I believe so, they are sincere
You were the first girl to treat me like that
What the hell is this?
What?
Do you know my heart that it always waits like this?
You are the best!
Isn't His Majesty the most respected?
I think this finger is quite good
Let me go! Hey!
If so, come back
First love?
I told her:
The 13th prince is handsome,
The 14th Prince is talented in martial arts
Told her to choose one of them
And this girl insisted on marrying the 10th prince
He is her first love
If I had known this would happen, I would have stopped her
But she wouldn't listen, she would still marry him
This is how my Soon Duk was
She's true to herself, that would never change
Let me ask you one thing
My Soon Deok
received a lot of love from the prince?
A lot
They loved each other
Okay then
It's good
Okay
Sorry, Soon Deok
Now your father...
Your father can't do anything for you
Soon Duk...
I'll kill him
Wang So... I'll kill him
No... No
I'll kill him
Before he kills everyone, I'll kill him!
Eun wanted this
This was Eun's wish
It's not his fault
It was hard for him too
Chi Mon
It looks like I
should become a killer dog
A dog that bites its owner
and will take over his farm
I'll become a rabid wolfhound
I, Wang So, will become the Emperor of Goryeo
Eun is dead
And his wife is dead too
Now Wang Gu's rebellion is not a fiction, but a fact
Congratulations
Now all clans will act in their own interests
We must hurry and make Seogyong the capital
This will satisfy Uncle Wang Sik Ryeom
There will be no funeral because he was called a traitor
We are not allowed to wear mourning clothes
They will not be buried in the cemetery for the imperial family,
and they will be thrown into the forest outside the palace to be devoured by crows
We will bury them secretly
We couldn't remove the arrows from Eun's body,
Jeong broke them
Eun...
still remembered my birthday
Even I already forgot about him
He said that only I could give this gift
Eun would be grateful for what you did for him
Prince So
I just found a letter
which Mrs. Su left for me
She wrote that the 10th prince was in Damiwon
Now in your eyes I must look like a monster
I killed Eun
It was a difficult choice
I know
Why did you hide the fact that he was in Damiwon?
You don't trust me, right?
She didn't say anything because she was afraid that I would kill him.
Yes
That's how it was
I was worried about the 10th prince
And I was afraid that you would have to do something terrible
I thought everything would go well and they would run away
I realized that we would hurt each other,
when it was too late
That's why I left a letter
I trusted you
I know it took time, but I trusted you
I could trust you in any situation,
because I realized that I like you
But now I don’t have such feelings
When I look at you
I remember what happened
due to lack of trust in me
Eun died because of you
I will remember how I killed him
To save you
I became the emperor's dog,
but my feelings remained unchanged
Now they've changed
I hide my tears deep inside
I want to forget everything about you
Let's stop
Lie
It's time for us to leave the fate that brought us together
You're lying
Even in tears we will live with you
We promised not to lie to each other
As if a free wind will carry you away
I kept looking for the way to you, but I never found it
I couldn’t catch the fate that was moving away from me
So I'll let you go completely
I was like a fallen petal
I was sad because I had to end it all like this
And if we meet again one day
Then we won’t say goodbye to you
Love
mine
4th Prince Wang So
The 10th Prince, the brother you stood up for, committed treason
You did a good job during the elimination of the prince and his wife Park Soon Deok
So you will get land and a house near Songak
It seems your spirit is now in a state of decline,
so go to the new capital, Seogyeong
You will be responsible for the construction of the palace
I trust this to you
I will dedicate myself to this cause
and I will repay you for your trust
Because of the blood shed...
aren't you scared?
It's hard to sit on the throne without spilling someone's blood
Be careful
There's a limit to what I can get away with
I will travel across the border and will not return to the palace
That's what you'll do
Still, think about your mother, don’t fight in the front ranks
Stay safe
I've lived like a coward for too long, so I can't
I want to see how long my life should be
I must pay for your crimes
For what you did to Eun
Brother!
Let us go!
Please! Brother!
We should take sacrificial food for the departed to the Kaeguksa Temple
Will you be responsible for the construction of the new palace?
You will become rich
He got it all by killing my daughter and son-in-law.
Long life to you
Is he even human? This is his little brother
I heard you want to become an emperor
Planned
That deceiver next to you said that you have been planning for a long time
He said that he saw your imperial star
That's what your late father Taejo said
That's why he sent you to me
Wanted me to teach you martial arts
All because of this
Imperial star?
I don't believe in such things
But I must become emperor
If I'm forced to kill for the throne...
I will own it and put an end to the killings.
Do you remember what the late emperor said earlier?
For the sake of the nation and the imperial family
the emperor must be ready to throw everything away
The throne will force you to give up a lot
I remember
Well then
who will you throw out?
I want to be the first to see this
Then I'll decide
When I see you I
I can’t breathe, I’m timid
It's as if everything in the world has stopped
Brother has already left for Sogyeong
He'll be there for a long time
If I pass by like a breeze,
you won't even notice
My heart is all given to you
But loving you is very painful for me
And so sad
I need to cross you out of my heart
I'll be waiting
so hard
Don't forget, please!
That eternal love of mine
But loving you is very painful for me
And so sad
I need to cross you out of my heart
so hard
I believe once upon a time
how I want to love
Senior lady! Senior lady!
I can
I told you, don't run
You are now a court lady, behave with dignity
Let's go quickly!
You'll be glad to see him!
Will I be happy?
Two years have passed since his departure! You'll be glad!
She asked me not to run
Long time no see
It's been a long time
Have a seat
I arrived two days early
I really wanted to drink your tea
But then I saw the place where Eun was buried...
I had to go there
I'm glad you went there
And I also looked at my daughter-in-law
I've done so much more than she ever did
You are now a general, I feel uncomfortable next to you
I was afraid that you would leave the palace during my absence
Where would I go?
What about marriage? Single?
A girl from a good family can leave the palace if she gets married
Should I get married and live my life taking care of someone?
I want to leave my position when I'm older
and go somewhere far, far away
I'll go to the desert, where I'll ride camels, I'll go to the ocean
I keep all the money that they paid me
Long time no see
Wow, how long has it been?
- I heard that you killed the Khitans in Khwai?
- Well, yes
My name is Woo Hee
This is the eldest court lady from the gisaeng house.
She came for tea and treats for Buddhists
The eldest lady of the gisaeng house?
Oh, that former gisaeng?
As always in bad company
Killer and now gisaeng
Watch your tongue
Be careful with this person
One day he might kill you
Besides, can you stop sending a musician to spy on the army?
Flute-playing spy?
I won't talk to you
Must have suffered a lot
once I began to suspect everyone
This guy... How did he know?
What a weasel
He may be a general, but there's something cute about him
Really? He's cute, right?
Did you really send someone?
I was wondering if he was doing everything right
By the way, what's wrong with So? What chambers is he in?
4th Prince...
arrived?
I just guessed whether he arrived or not...
Yo
Your Majesty
Jeong is back. You have to make a decision
Mother of Gyeong Jong Won Geun of Hubaekje
You can't give Goryeo to someone with Hubaekje blood.
Make Jeong crown prince
You need someone to watch your back, Your Majesty
Mother, how do you see me?
Am I a man or a pig?
You probably don't see me as a son,
but only a boar, which you must sacrifice in exchange for the throne
It's not like I'm going to die soon,
but you've been tormenting me for years
Jeong...
Does he want to take the throne?
His Highness the 4th Prince wishes to see His Majesty
If you are so afraid, I will do it with the crown prince
Jeong or Seo, they are both your sons
What are you talking about?!
We'll discuss this later!
You're so useful
What's wrong with a few dead slaves?
to stop construction again?!
The lands in Songak are weakening
The line of the imperial family is in danger
Both monks and shamans confirmed this
We don't have enough manpower
We don't have enough supplies, so people work one day and rest the next
If you miss people, just don't let them sleep
Not enough supplies - steal them if necessary
Squeeze, squeeze all the strength out of them!
Finish everything on time
I have committed a mortal sin, Your Majesty
Your Majesty, let's continue the conversation in private
Are you still awake?
I haven't seen you sleep well since I entered Damiwon.
I'll go to bed soon
What is it that you write so often lately?
You're illiterate, but you noticed
Yes, I'm illiterate, but I'm not blind
Looks exactly the same
I like the meaning
“It happened that I would reach the very sources of the stream,”
"Squatting down, I contemplate how the clouds rise in the distance"
He's a fool for coming all the way to the water
If you can't sleep, maybe take a walk?
Will you leave without seeing me?
In these two years you have never come to me
It seems they really forgot me
Yes
I came here today by mistake
I will become the darkness
Nothing is over for me
And I'll wrap you in myself
So bear with me since you left without my consent
Just for a day, just like that
I... deserve at least this
Stay with me
And I will become the moon
I will be the light for one
Wherever I am, wherever I go, I will come
Are you sleeping well?
Are you eating well?
You are my love, believe me
Still
You're the only one I need so much
are you offended by me?
I look at you from afar
And I'll turn away again
Here I confess to you alone
With all my strength I
Love, love, love
Can you hear my heart now?
Prince Wang So communicates closely
with some clans from Songak,
he specifically prevents the construction of the palace
He mixed gravel so the walls fell apart
and released some workers
Are you sure?
There were also rumors
that because of Wang Sik Ryeom's illness
no one is monitoring the construction
Why? Why?! Why?!
What does he need?
He didn't just go against my will...
Throne...
Is he aiming for the throne?
Right?
Let me ask you first
Why did they violate our agreement?
Agreement?
People who cannot pay tribute
sent to forced labor
Poor people from Hupaekje
sent to a construction site where they die
What's the point of continuing to be
with your eyes and ears?
And what? Do you want to leave?
If there is no benefit for me
Princess Woo Hee
You didn't behave like that, did you?
Do you know about Back A?
His soul is very vulnerable and sensitive
People of art, as a rule, are all like that
I wonder what expression will be on his face
when will he find out that you are my dog?
I'm not alone, so it's okay
The prince is with me! Why am I alone?
You said you needed permission?
Will you hear him?
- Can?
- It is forbidden
The same voice that is in such a hurry to confess
In the future... don't forget these words
Are you still listening?
Can you hear my heart?
How raindrops settled on the window
Also my mind is consumed by you
Need you
Still
I miss you
are you offended by me?
From over there
And Hae Soo with him
Take a look at them
I told you, you can rest assured that he will be your faithful dog, Your Majesty
He'll be useful if I put a collar on him right now
"These two don't have feelings for each other anymore, so it won't work."
Do you believe it?
I was told that they don't send each other any letters
You still need to confirm it
Slaves work well only when
if you flog them from time to time
Stop
It would be better not to see you at all
Are you okay?
It seemed to me that my hand was weakening,
so I decided to check myself
Are you hurt?
It barely hit me
So you two are still on good terms
If you killed a lady of the court for fun, not very good rumors would spread
Yes, that wouldn't be good
I didn't think
Be careful
What did I do?
Did you want to see me?
Can you convey a message to Baek Ah?
Near Songak
He was heading to Seogyong
His hand began to hurt even more, so he resorted to treatment
I sent everyone away, don't worry
I'm still looking at you from the outside
It seemed to me that you are my love
I kept thinking that you feel the same way
Although you look the other way
Like the wind, like dust
I can't catch you and see you
Do you remember: I love, I love
I believe there was love, I’ll call it fate
In your eyes, I settled in your gaze
And I can only answer you:
Hold me if I'm swinging
my love
Why are you here?
I have to ask something
I asked Baek Ah for a favor
Ask and leave
Are you still
have you forgotten me?
You said you don't like me anymore
You lied?
Come back
This is not a palace, the emperor will not see us
I wanted to ask you a question,
therefore, risking her life, she left the palace
There wasn't a day when I wasn't waiting for you
I want to go back to that time...
I wish this again and again
Therefore...
I wanted to say
that I believe you
I'll ask again
Answer me, but don't lie
Reply
Are you still
love
me?
Because I'm next to you, I'm very happy
Because I'm next to you, I keep dreaming
Because I'm next to you, I smile so brightly
For you to be mine, I always pray to the Gods
If you see my love and my feelings
If you find my love and the path to me
I will give my heart completely
If you can stay with me for the rest of your life
Because you are next to me, I am grateful
Because you are next to me, I always feel warm
Nice, right?
Come here, come here
Because you are next to me, even in spirit I am strong
I look at you and cry bitterly
If you see my love and my feelings
If you find my love and the path to me
I will give my heart completely
This square is Pegasus
If you can stay with me for the rest of your life
W... what?
- Pegasus
- Pe...
Pesos
I'm with you
The Emperor is very sick
The monk was about to perform sacrificial rites
We thought we could scare the emperor
so we chose the day
when lightning was supposed to strike
We didn’t even think that the monk would die because of this very lightning strike
Doctors say
it amazed him greatly, so he weakened
Help me get out, Yo!
Brother! Please let us go!
Think about how we grew up together
I will never return to Goryeo again!
Yo
His Majesty?
No...
Don't... don't come near!
Yo
Don't come near! Don't come near! Don't come near!
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
Call the court physician! Immediately!
Prepare your horse
I will go to Seogyeong to see Wang Sik Ryeom!
I think the time has come
Princes Wook and Jeong left,
while General Park and the Kang family of Shinju control the court army and other clans
You have to make a decision
Do you want to take the throne?
I want
The reason you left me...
Was it because of the throne?
The Emperor used you to get to me
He will use me to bother you
What if I asked you to give up?
I'll convince you until you say I have to do it
You said that as long as we are together,
you don't need to be an emperor
Don't you say that anymore
We agreed not to lie to each other
I started this, I have to stop the brothers from killing each other
But...
When I was building the palace,
I realized that the world can change if the ruler who rules it changes
I don't want to be controlled
And I can get rid of all this absurdity
Become an emperor -
what I want
Thanks for watching with us!
Release group MANIA
http://doramamania.mybb.ru
http://vk.com/doramamania
Scarlet Hearts: Ryeo
Another place and another time here, but I believe, you are my love
It's all because of you, girl! Because of your interference!
If you want to become the owner of a palace,
must sacrifice something
A fair wind will bring your scent, it’s so easy for me to recognize it
- Long life to the emperor!
You may suddenly pass by and not notice, have you forgotten me?
You are just a thief who stole the throne from my son!
You said that wanting both you and the throne is greed
But until you remember me, I will wait for you
How can I accept this?
Kill!
Don't miss out
At the same time, in the same place we will be...
none